## Jirawat Akkanit

## **Digital Transformation Strategist**

danjirawat@gmail.com

## Summary

Jirawat Akkanit is a Founder and Managing Director at Techcon Cybernet. He has a great passion and experience working in the digital space more than 20 years. He has the ability to oversee implementation and operation of front-end and backend services such as web, app, e-commerce, mobile app, digital and multimedia publishing, digital marketing and advertising for delivering the best class digital experiences to customer.

He has experience of managing a multi-skilled team combined with technical experience working with digital environment, web applications, enterprise applications, e-commerce solutions and relational databases. He has knowledge of mobile app eco-systems including iOS and Android application design and development. He has experience overseeing implementation and operation of cloud platforms. He provides consultancy to both private and government firm in the area of digital transformation solutions.

Jirawat holds bachelor's and master's degrees in Medical Technology at Chiangmai University and Mahidol University, respectively.

# Experience

## Managing Director at Techcon Cybernet Co.,Ltd.

January 2007 - Present (9 years 6 months)

- Oversees the company's implementation and operation of front-end and backend services such as web, app, e-commerce, mobile app, digital and multimedia publishing, digital marketing and advertising.
- Collaborate with UX/UI designers on wire-framing and visual design and collaborate with development and QA teams to launch new products.
- Establish relationships with the advertising agencies, marketing consultants and other companies looking for outsourcing mobile and web application solutions.
- Partnerships with the professional web and mobile developers around the world
- Provides consultancy to both private and government firm in the area of responsive web design, web hosting, e-commerce, e-business, mobile application development, digital publishing and multimedia production, 2D & 3D animation, search engine optimization (SEO), social media solutions, geolocation and augmented reality (AR) solutions.

## Digital Marketing and Technology Consultant at Siam Nutra Co., Ltd.

March 2013 - June 2015 (2 years 4 months)

Provide digital marketing and technology strategies to the company including mobile application development, e-commerce development, payment gateway integration, social media implementation and other online media strategies.

## Vice President - Venture Capital at Stang Holding Co., Ltd.

2005 - 2007 (2 years)

- Manages all Mahidol University's commercial research and consultancy partnerships
- Forms new business ventures based on research and develops the University's intellectual property estate
- Seeking for a good business opportunity as a business development chief
- Supervise the analyst team to perform industry and market analysis of targeted investment companies
- Prepare a business assessment and feasibility studies
- Conduct a business due diligence including company analysis and financial analysis
- Co-ordinate with the strategic partners, investors and customers both local and oversea
- Conduct the presentation to the investment boards for approval

## Managing Director at Multiply Travel Corporation Co., Ltd.

2003 - 2005 (2 years)

Provide travel related e-businesses including e-ticketing, accommodation and recreation services. Provide online reservation system via the Internet and electronic media

## Managing Director at Catamaran Samui Corporation Co., Ltd.

2003 - 2005 (2 years)

Provide 200 seats high speed catamaran service from Koh Samui to Koh Phangan and Koh Tao. Develop online booking facilities for seat reservation system integrated with E-Payment from Bank of Ayudhya

## Senior Product Manager at Samart Telcom PCL.

2001 - 2003 (2 years)

Developed and implemented e-business development, specialize in travel industry, managed budgets, designed press releases and promotional materials.

- Analyzed economic conditions, business trends and potential markets as a project manager
- Develop a marketing plan, action plan, budgeting and financial forecast
- Managed the implementation of high speed Internet in room and Wi-Fi hot spot for hotels
- Evaluated new software and hardware to determine compatibility with existing software and hardware
- Constantly looked for and discovering simpler and more effective methods of streamlining operations
- Provide service to Imperial Queen's Park Hotel, Pathumwan Princess Hotel, Century Park Hotel, Tai-pan Hotel, Le Meridian Baan Taling Ngam Samui, Chaweng Regent Samui, Samui Peninsula Resort and Spa and Natural Park Service Apartment Bangkok.

## Web Production Manager at Samart Internet Co., Ltd.

1998 - 2001 (3 years)

Directed, designed, developed, and implemented a secure interactive Web site with a suite of applications, an authentication server, and a server for secure Web transactions.

- Managed Department of Export Promotion's projects value 20 Million Baht, with an average project budget savings of 15% under estimation
- Recruited, trained, and supervised a team of 100 outsourcing Web builders
- Provided support to 780 exporters by coordinating call center services such as seminar events, progress reports and trainings
- Proven ability to synchronize large amounts of information from 780 exporters to create complete E-Commerce Websites
- Proven track records in business and government relations
- Proficient in developing Web building procedures and templates to improve Web development efficiency
- Proficiency in developing and implementing effective training programs for Web builders and exporters

## Webmaster at Chulalongkorn University Book Center

1997 - 1998 (1 year)

Pioneered the first E-Commerce Website in Thailand for online ordering and payment gateway integration.

- Converted ordering system from a manual to a computerized system by building an E-Commerce Website for Chulalongkorn University Bookstore
- First Thai online bookstore which implemented a real-time credit card processing from Siam Commercial Bank (SCB)
- Managed book inventory of 100,000 book titles in MS-SQL database
- Created procedures for handling special customer orders such as librarian customers
- Demonstrated success in advancing rapid growth and generating substantial profits from 30,000 Baht per month to more than 300,000 Baht per month of ordering via Websites within 5 months

#### Multimedia Production Manager at Mekong Media Co., Ltd.

1995 - 1997 (2 years)

Led the production of multimedia E-Catalog CD-ROM, Website and interactive media

## **Test Scores**

#### **TU-GET**

January 2008 Score: 780/1000

The TU-GET is a test of English language proficiency required for Thammasat University's undergraduate and graduate students.

# Volunteer Experience

# Public helath checkup volunteer at Chiang Mai University, Faculty of Associate Medical Sciences (AMS)

1990 - 1993

Students from 5 faculties of health-related (doctor, nurse, pharmacy, dentistry and AMS) coordinated each year to provide public health checkup services.

## Certifications

## **Developing Web Application Using Informix i.Sell**

Informix Software 2001

## **Publications**

## **Smart ICT Section**

Thai Hotel Association (THA) Newsletter Volume 1 - 6 January 2004

Authors: Jirawat Akkanit

Smart ICT e-business solutions for hotels and resorts such as Online Hotel reservation / Property

Management System / VoIP/ IPStar / In Room High Speed Internet Service for hotels / Cable TV in room

## **Samart's Internet Production System**

Informix Magazine April 2001

Authors: Jirawat Akkanit

This article is about Samart's Collaborative Website for Web Developers to collaborate using Informix's Web technology

## Honors and Awards

## **Managerial Excellent Award**

Samart Corporation PCL.

2001

Managed projects for Department of Export Promotion (DEP) value 20 Million Baht with an average project budget savings of 15% under estimation and close the project prior to the deadline

## Keynote Speaker on BlackBerry Jam Asia 2012

Blackberry Limited

November 2012

Jirawat has been invited to be a keynote speaker on BlackBerry Jam Asia 2012 event in Bangkok, Thailand.

To discuss the basic building blocks of Sencha Touch applications and the new BlackBerry® 10 components that are being made available to get that native look and feel in Sencha application.

## **Blazer for Outstanding Employee**

Chulalongkorn University Book Center

1998

Demonstrated success in advancing rapid growth and generating substantial profits in only 5 months

## Winner Award, Coke Music Award

Coca-Cola (Thailand) Co.,Ltd.

1995

Coke Music Award (band competition)

## Winner Award, Folk Song Festival

The faculty of Agriculture, Chiang Mai University

1990

Annual Folk Song Festival of The faculty of Agriculture, Chiang Mai University

## **Research Scholarships**

Institute of Molecular Biology and Genetics (IMBG), Mahidol University 1994

Research Scholarships for Master Degree

## Languages

Thai

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

**English** 

(Professional working proficiency)

## Skills & Expertise

**Mobile Applications** 

**Web Applications** 

HTML 5

E-commerce

**Web Development** 

**CSS** 

**Mobile Devices** 

Web Design

**PHP** 

CSS3

Joomla

**jQuery** 

iOS development

**Photoshop** 

**MySQL** 

**Android Development** 

**XML** 

**AJAX** 

Sencha

HTML5

**Objective-C** 

Sencha Touch

**Lead Generation** 

**Strategic Planning** 

**New Business Development** 

**Digital Marketing** 

**Digital Strategy** 

**Marketing Strategy** 

**Social Media Marketing** 

**Entrepreneurship** 

**Business Planning** 

**Business Analysis** 

**Business Strategy** 

**Business Development** 

**Online Marketing** 

WordPress

Vue.js

**Firebase** 

**Bootstrap** 

**Apache Cordova** 

**Swift** 

**JavaScript** 

CoffeeScript

**Web Analytics** 

**Web Services** 

**Web Content Management** 

Illustrator

Hype

**Github** 

**Android Studio** 

## Education

## **Mahidol University**

Master of Science (M.Sc.), Medical Technology, 1994 - 1996

Activities and Societies: Join the Medical Technology Faculty's music band.

## **Chiangmai University**

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Medical Technology, 1990 - 1993

Activities and Societies: President of the student, join the faculty music band, debate team, public health checkup volunteer, blood collection unit volunteer

## **Interests**

Mobile Technology, Web Technology, Smart Devices, New Innovation Gadget, Musical Instruments, Travel, Movie, Photography, Game, Sport, Exercise, Reading

# Jirawat Akkanit

Digital Transformation Strategist

danjirawat@gmail.com



Contact Jirawat on LinkedIn